DAVID ROOBAN V

Mobile: +918608710777 · Mail: davidrvincent1@gmail.com · LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/david-rooban-vincent-52490614a

Residence: Puducherry, India

SAP TECHNICAL CONSULTANT

A highly skilled SAP Technical Consultant with 4+ years of experience, with demonstrated history of working in implementation projects for one of the world's largest public oil and gas producers. Proficient in SAP technologies such as S4 ABAP, OOABAP, OData, CDS/AMDP, UI5 and Fiori, with additional experience in Java Script, HTML, and CSS. Known for being self-motivated, flexible, and reliable, with strong communication and soft skills.

SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

- ABAP / ABAP on HANA / OOABAP
- Reports, Module Pool
- Enhancements
- · Forms, RFC, BAPI
- SAP OData
- · CDS Views, AMDP
- Ui5 Programming
- Fiori applications
- Java Script, HTML, CSS
- · Team Leadership
- Multitasking
- Professional Communication
- · Team Play

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KAAR TECHNOLOGIES Senior Analyst, MENA North Region

October 2023 - Present Chennai, India

- Worked on Shared Services, handling various customers such as manufacturing, military, banking and sales.
- Implemented various Change Requests for the national banks of Kuwait, enabling customer payments through payment gateway services using ABAP on HANA concepts.
- Developed custom reports and Module pool programs for various FICO and MM processes.
- · Worked on Enhancements of standard reports based on customer requirements.
- · Worked on Fiori apps activation and T-code as tile functionality
- Worked on Ui5 application change requests to add new features and enhancing application performance.
- · Worked on Data Dictionary objects, custom Workflows, Function Modules and documentation.
- · Worked on OData services development to integrate with CPI/ C4C.
- Worked as Team Lead, managing 3 resources and ensured on time object deliveries for various customers.

KAAR TECHNOLOGIES Technical Analyst, Delivery

August 2022 - September 2023 Chennai, India

- Implemented new process cycles and additional features/functionalities for Supplier Performance, Supplier Qualification and Subcontracting custom applications for the world's largest Oil and Gas company.
- · Built various OData models/ custom OData services and handled all types of OData requests.
- Worked on Ui5 objects to build new pages, additional fragments and UI functionalities to help simplify the user experience using OOABAP concepts.
- · Developed Function modules, Reports and various data dictionary objects.
- Involved in all the project meetings with customer, such as requirement gathering, UAT sessions and Business Testing sessions.
- · Worked on UAT Scripts, Test documents, User Manuals and FAQ User guides.

KAAR TECHNOLOGIES - ALBILAD ARABIA Ltd Technical Consultant

April 2021 - July 2022 Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

- Worked on Centralized Ui5 application and Mobile Application implementation for managing entire EHSM processes for the world's largest Oil and Gas company.
- Developed professional rapport with the customer through In Person meetings and review sessions at the customer location.
- Worked on various OData objects to perform CRUD operations and integrating it to the respective Ui5 and Flutter applications.
- Worked on Ui5 development, building custom Ui5 application with HTML/XML and JavaScript in the front end
- · Worked on Data dictionary objects, reports and Custom Workflows.
- · Involved in Go-live activities, documentation and Hypercare support.

KAAR TECHNOLOGIES Associate Consultant

October 2020 - March 2021 Chennai, India

- Developed internal Portal Application that connects customers, vendors and employees of the organization.
- Worked on Angular JS as front end, connecting SAP through PIPO, performing data collection logic through RFCs.
- Involved in code review sessions and performance evaluation sessions.
- · Worked on Technical Specification documents and User Manuals.

AWARDS

- Star Employee 2023-2024: Awarded Rs.10,000 cash prize for exhibiting impressive performance as a Senior Analyst.
- Rising star Award, 2023: In appreciation of the tremendous support and constant contributions to the company
- Got featured in Humans of Kaar series, featured in Kaar Technologies Social Media Platforms for excelling in non-project activities.
- Star of the Month Award, 2022: In appreciation for the extended support beyond the mainstream support period in closing the critical activities of the project

EDUCATION

Rajiv Gandhi College of Engineering & Technology B.Tech - Computer Science and Engineering

CGPA: 8.8

SDA Hr.Sec School, Puducherry.

HSC graduation Percentage: 85.5% **Pondicherry University**

Tamil Nadu Stateboard

AGENCY EXPIRED CANDIDATE

Rooban, David

8608710777 davidrvincent1@gmail.com